hey everyone welcome back to our Channel
I am back with another interesting topic
in the tosa automation
playlist so today we are going to talk
about a common issue which you might
have faced earlier or you might face uh
when you working with tosa and that is
um when you make a mistake while working
in a project which uh is a multi-user
workspace and you are working in a team
now think that uh by mistake you deleted
a particular object which might be a
test case uh which might be a module or
um which might be execution list or any
object uh within tosa right which was
already present in the project and then
you miss stenly uh deleted that
particular object now you would think
that there is no way to recover that
particular object in your TSA project
but uh that's not true okay uh
especially not true if your project has
got versioning
enabled so let's see how this particular
uh issue could be resolved um even
though it looks uh improvable it is
actually possible to recover a deleted
object in tosa so um I am currently in a
multi-user workspace okay and I will
show you this particular example or demo
on this particular folder which is the
project folder which I have created with
some test cases uh and some test steps
inside this right so this is the folder
where we are working now before moving
forward we need to First make sure that
versioning is enabled for about this
particular workspace or project okay and
that you can do uh by going into the uh
menu bar there you will find a tab uh
which is
versioning right and here you will see
there are three option uh view change
history for project view recovered and
lost objects and manage versioning okay
so if you click on manage versioning uh
you will see that versioning is enabled
okay I can also enable this delete this
day and older I can choose a particular
day and uh Beyond this it will try to
remove everything okay or delete this
revision and older so I can put a
version number here and Beyond this it
is going to uh or below this it is going
to remove all the other versions now if
I want I can also disable the
versioning um it will say that disabling
the version permanently deletes your
entire version history and it will ask
you to confirm or cancel okay so mostly
I would not recommend to disable the
version unless you have got space
constraints because if we enable the
first thing then um your workspace size
is going to increase because um it is
always going to maintain a particular
number of versions for your every object
in the workspace so if you got a huge
workspace and then you have enabled
vering then um it will uh consume a lot
of space but uh versing is um
recommended and also important because
of these kind of scenarios where um you
need uh some backup for all of your
objects right so if by mistake um you
lose some object or your workspace gets
corrupted and uh you are not able to
save or check in your objects right in
those kind of scenarios versioning uh
may be helpful okay so um this is about
manage versioning uh I can also see view
recovered and uh lost objects okay so it
will show you which objects were lost
right if I search right now I cannot see
um any lost objects in my
workspace and then um I can also see the
change history for the complete project
okay so here you can see the change
history for the complete project these
are all the versions you can see here
and when you click on a version it will
tell you what was done okay so this
particular demo
folder uh one object was updated right
in this folder then in this test case
one object was deleted and then in this
test case one object was
added okay this is how it shows you all
the different versions and uh what was
done in that particular version also the
unique ID uh through which you can
search
it okay so this is for the whole
project now coming to our particular
scenario right so here we have got uh
the project folder so we will go out and
check out the tree here and then uh by
mistake uh we actually deleted uh the
test case three
okay now there could be several reasons
you thought it is not needed uh you
thought you would create a new test case
or due to any reason you just deleted
this particular test case and then you
also performed a checkin all so which
makes sure that all the changes are
checked in right which are not
reversible anyways because there is no
option to reverse your changes or to
recover that particular test case
directly okay so there is no direct
option like that in tosa and then most
people think that once a object is
deleted in tosa it is not possible to
recover right so what they do they try
and recreate all the objects which uh
were removed by mistake but that's not
correct okay so now what we will do here
uh we'll check out the whole project
okay and now uh we will
also let's add another test case here uh
which is called tc4 not TC3 uh which I
deleted and then I'm going to check in
all now how can I recover the lost
object so uh right click on the project
okay uh which is the test case folder
and then you will find a versioning uh
in the menu okay so this is the option
versioning option and there are three
options view change history uh view
change history for tree or uh export
subset for revision so either we can
view the change history for the
individual object or we can uh view the
change history for the tree which means
it will show the change history not only
for the folder but also for for all the
objects which are contained inside that
folder because we are looking at the
tree so now if I look at the version
history for this particular tree right
you will see there are two versions okay
so one is
30 okay so here what it is showing me
zero objects updated right uh zero
objects were added and four objects were
deleted right and if you notice this is
the test case three which we deleted by
mistake and then here one object updated
right in the project
folder then um if I go into this the
last version which is 26 in this you
will see uh one object added then the
test case one test case 2 and test case
three right
so whenever you are trying to recover uh
any particular object uh and you're
looking at the uh change history you
always need to uh choose the option or
you always need to look at the revision
number uh prior to uh the number which
uh shows that you have deleted that
particular object which is for our case
it is 30 here right but uh we need to
use the revision number 26 so that we
can recover the earlier version of this
three or this particular test cases so
what it will do it will recover test
case 3 which is not present in our
folder so uh you cannot directly do this
from here so uh let's close this option
and let's come back here now um here
there were three options right so now
what we'll do we have to export subset
for a particular revision so we will
choose this option
here and now it will ask you to select a
revision which is between 1 to 30 okay
so we are going to choose a division
which is
26 right so what we will do here uh we
will click on okay and then it will ask
you to save this particular subset now
it is just like uh Import and Export
subset uh which we have used multiple
times to Import and Export different
objects but this particular option is
made to export a particular revision
right so which is a version saved in
tosa and then you create a export subset
out of it right so I'm going to call
this TC3 uh. TSU which is the tosa
subset and click on Save
okay once uh this message comes which is
export subset for revision
finished which means it was uh
exported now uh what we going to do is
we are going to check out
all now once uh you have successfully
exported your revision now we need to
import that particular subset right
which we
created now uh when I click on this
folder you will see that import subset
is not any build now this is correct
because when you import a subset a
number of different objects are used
right it could be in modules folder it
could be in execution folder so the best
way uh to enable the import subset
option is to also check out the project
right because um tosa will need uh to
merge different objects okay once you do
that you will see the import subset
option is enabled again right so
whenever you find import subset not
enabled you can do
this now uh we will select our project
folder and we will import subset uh we
will select the subset which we
created now um it will tell you when
mergeable objects found and this is
probably the module which I used which
was a standard module which is already
present okay so you can choose either
options uh if you choose the import op
option it will um again create a
different folder out of it um but if you
want to merge the existing objects
that's fine you can do that
okay so we will choose that option which
is to merge that particular object now
the only problem here uh Is It Anyways
creates a new folder uh which is the
test case import and uh it Imports
everything okay uh instead of the test
case three which is not ideal um it
should have merged everything into the
same
folder but it doesn't do that okay so in
these kind of cases um obviously what we
need to do is we will take the required
object from here and then we will paste
it here so now we have recovered the
test case three so now what uh you can
do is if you don't require um these test
cases which are kind of a duplic
that which was imported uh what you can
simply do is you can go ahead and delete
all these objects which are not required
okay and then you you can bring your
workspace to the exact state which was
previous uh to when you created the test
case 4 which is the test case 3 which
was removed by mistake and which is now
been recovered
okay so now I can check in all and now I
have got all my objects uh without
recreating that object I used uh the
versioning uh to get a different version
of uh a test case which was removed
earlier but it could be recovered using
that particular version okay so viring
is quite powerful if that feature is
enabled for your project you can recover
um any version of a particular object
which is either lost or uh if you want
to get a version of your previous change
also um so which means you want to
revert your change you can do it this
way that's all for this particular video
if you have any questions then please
leave it in the comments if you like
this video then please subscribe to our
Channel thanks for watching and I will
see you in the next
video